### **ELIZABETH BETSON**

Phone: (312) 523-6571 | Email: hire.elizabethb@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/elizabethbetson | Portfolio: www.elizabethbetson.com

#### SUMMARY

Accomplished full stack web developer with sales background and 5+ years of experience in technology, marketing, and nonprofit expansion to create user-friendly, interactive experiences. Exceptional leadership, public speaking, and written communication (both English and basic Spanish), relationship-building, analytical, and problem resolution skills. Thrives in both independent and collaborative work environments and embraces a life-long dedication to continued learning.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | jQuery | Bootstrap | Express.js | React.js | Node.js | Database Theory | MongoDB | MySQL | Git | Javascript | React

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

### Account Executive, Bracing Specialist VQ Orthocare

2017-2018

Los Angeles, CA

Connected doctors and patients with liaison support and one-on-one consultations.

- Aided hospitals, clinics, and patients in understanding intricacies of billing and insurance, greatly reducing pain points.
- · Led state team in new accounts opened.

## Field Agent, Product Specialist Alma Lasers

2015 - 2017

Los Angeles, CA

Built robust client base and programmed route efficiencies to maximize potential customer outreach.

• Advanced from Sales Representative to Product Specialist, closing \$400,000 within six months with \$2 million actively working in pipeline.

### **Independent, Broker Sales Representative**

2014 – 2016

Los Angeles, CA

Developed budget solutions and strategies for both small businesses and Fortune 500 companies.

- Proven sales leader and hunter, receiving "Fast Start" and "Fireball" recognition by writing \$25,000 in traditional gross annual premiums within first three months utilizing SPIN and solutions-based selling.
- Promoted from Independent Sales Representative in less than one month—a record for the Southern California region.

#### ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intern, Sales Consultant DAC Management

Aflac

2013-2020

Chicago, IL; Hong Kong

Communicated detailed technical medical and financial research to business owners and executive management team.

- Advanced quickly within the company to aid in the acquisition of Medical Entrepreneurs II, Inc's groundbreaking cardiology biotechnology.
- Assists current expansion in API creation for competitive financial global markets.

## CTO, Front-End Developer Eco Preservation Project

2018– Present Chicago, IL; Miami, FL

Created interactive ecommerce and scheduling application for nonprofit charity (ecopreservation project.com).

 Increased profits and donations by over 3000% in past six months, earning promotion to C-level executive seat.

### **EDUCATION**

### Bootcamp Certificate: Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

# Bachelor of Science in Biology, minor in Psychology (with Honors): DePaul University, Chicago, IL

Two-time published co-author for *Journal of Macromolecular Science, Part A: Pure and Applied Chemistry* 

Associates Degree, Certified Nurses' Aide: Labette Community College, Parsons, KS

### **PROJECTS**

### BuzzKillR | https://bit.ly/buzzkillr | buzzkillr.herokuapp.com

- A social network for reporting and aggregating data about night life wait times and bouncer behavior.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: Node, Express, React

### EcoCoat | https://bit.ly/ecocoatgit | chicacoat.herokuapp.com

- A full stack web application that is an eco-friendly winter wear drop shipping alternative.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: Node, MySql, Express, Sequelize, Passport

### Future Forecast Finder | https://bit.ly/forecastgit | https://bit.ly/fforecastfinder

- A front-end application that predicts climate change over time.
- Front-End Development, Design
- Languages: AJAX, Meteostat API, Graph.js